RUSSELL MASATO

Blockchain Developer

https://github.com/Russell1130 @ devlord0625@gmail.com Windsor, Ontario, CA

SKILLS

HTML & CSS

Javascript/Typescript Angular

Vue/Nuxt React/Next

NodeJS MongoDB Python

PHP Ruby Django

Blockchain Technology

Cryptography

Consenus Algorithms

Smart Contracts

Distributed Systems

Data Structures

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science

University of Windsor

INDUSTRY EXPERTISE

DeFi Protocols



Web Development

SUMMARY

I am a full stack engineer with 6 years of experience with strong skills in Solidity, Rust, Javascript, Node.is, React.is, C++, Django and PHP. Specialize in Solidity, Smart Contracts, ether.js, web3.js, and JS/TS frameworks and familiar with several blockchain networks like Ethereum, Binance, Tron, Polkadot, Tezos, Polygon, Huobi ECO chain, etc.

EXPERIENCE

Blockchain Developer

Decentral Inc(Remote)

1 01/2021 - 10/2022 Ontario, CA

Decentral Inc. is Canada's leading blockchain company, founded in 2014 by Anthony Di Iorio. Decentral is a Toronto-based innovation hub and software development company focused on decentralized technologies.

- Worked on the development and implementation of new blockchain technologies and completed professional market research.
- · Built and maintained strategic relationships with potential investors and business partners and brainstormed new ideas.
- Collaborated with colleagues from other departments and participated in the creation and testing of new software applications.

Frontend Developer

IQ Hunt Ltd(Remote)

6 06/2019 - 12/2020 Ontario, CA

IQ Hunt is a premier provider of I.T. Contract & Permanent Staff to companies in Southern Ontario.

- Contributed to the in-house UI library to create reusable components that saved 140 hours of development time monthly
- · Created a web app MVP for a store delivery management platform with 100+ business customers to create, manage, and monitor deliveries using React and Redux
- Added new features to a meditation app with 30,000+ monthly active users to enable the uploading of audio and video content using React and Redux

Backend Developer

Safe Software(Remote)

1 02/2018 - 05/2019 Paritish Columbia, CA

Safe Software develops and delivers FME, the data integration platform with the best support for spatial data worldwide.

- Reduced deployment time from 72 hours to 50 minutes by building 14 tools to automate deployment processes using Jenkins Pipelines and Kubernetes Jobs.
- Supported the development of 28 new features such as user authentication & authorization, course management system (CMS), and student information system (SIS) by designing APIs for an Edtech site.
- Developed a microservices-based architecture with Node.js, Kubernetes, Docker, MySQL/PostgreSQL, and Elasticsearch for 15 online education platforms that serve 1.5M users hourly.

My Previous works





Defi Bids https://defibids.com/

DefiBids is the world's first cryptocurrency auction site. This smart contract is based on Uniswap

- I developed first page of this project.
- Also developed smart contract myself.

Here, you can see contract of this project.

https://etherscan.io/address/0x1dA01e84F3d4e6716F274c987Ae4bEE5DC3C8288#code

UniFarm https://unifarm.co/

UniFarm enables value creation for investors where they can stake one token and earn multiple tokens as reward.

- I developed dashboard of this project.
- Also developed smart contract myself.

Here, you can see contract of this project.

https://etherscan.io/address/0x40986a85b4cfcdb054a6cbfb1210194fee51af88#code